Prabhjot Singh

singh.prabhjot@outlook.com +1 6047734313 Vancouver, BC

Summary

Software engineer with around 10 years of experience in the tech industry. Worked on various areas like contributing to the open source Google Chromium, large scale backend technologies for global Amazon transportation, owned multiple items as part of Azure SQL team such as CI/CD, ownership mapping, developing multiple user interfaces, and working extensively on data warehousing and SQL. I have also taken around 200 interviews for Amazon. Looking for a challenging role in software engineering that leverages my skills and experience.

Experience

Senior Software Engineer

Microsoft • Vancouver, BC

06/2022 - Present

(1 year 5 months)

Working as a senior software engineer at Microsoft Azure SQL Engineering Systems. I work full stack on .Net, blazor framework and own multiple UI experiences end to end along with their APIs

Software Development Engineer 2

Amazon 08/2019 - 06/2022

(2 years 11 months)

I was part of middle mile transportation team where i worked on various backend services to support global Amazon middle mile transportation network. I also worked extensively owned the Datawarehouse for all services owned by my Team.

Software Development Engineer

Amazon 08/2016 - 08/2019

(1 year 9 months)

I was part of Core Transportation technologies team in Amazon India office. Worked on following

- Redirect to Locker: Delivering package to locker if customer is not available
- Created various micro services for handling platform improvements such as creating a facade layer for having document heavy request processing separately.
- Created a generic bug reporting framework from a service

Software Development Engineer

Amazon 07/2014 - 07/2016

(2 years 2 months)

properly.

I joined Amazon Lab126 team as SDE1 where i worked on following major projects over the course of my time

Open source libraries such as Chromium Webview which is used in most of the Android applications on Amazon app store. My responsibilities involved upgrading this library to latest version in open source, fixing compatibility issues with current Android app suit, making optimizations and other bug fixes. Also worked on Cordova open source library which is used by many engineers across the globe for writing Android applications without knowing how to program in Android platform. Here my responsibilities included bug fixes, application compatibility and upgrading cordova to latest versions.

Porting Chromium webview to smaller/compact devices where optimizations were required for it to work

Android framework changes where bug fixes or application compatibility changes were required.

Software Development Engineer, Intern

Amazon (6 months)

As part of internship project i created a proof of concept unique Android application for Kindle devices which was used to gather all user activities into one app in various different views.

Skills

Application Programming Interfaces (API), Core Java, Java, C, Data Structures, MySQL, JavaScript, C++, Algorithm Design, System Design, CI/CD, AWS, Azure, Android, Chromium, Cordova, Data Warehouse, Spring, Microservices

Education

Masters in Computer Applications

University of Delhi • New Delhi

01/2014

- · India wide entrance exam rank holder
- Multiple subject topper like Artificial Intelligence, Algorithms, Data structures

Bachelor of Computer Science

University of Delhi • New Delhi

01/2011

- · College Topper
- Multiple subject Top University Wide (like Algebra, OS, Statistics)